JUDY BUI

Canada · 647-674-3357 · judybui712@gmail.com · LinkedIn · GitHub · Portfolio

Experienced Full Stack Software Engineer with a strong background in the industry and passion about building impactful projects that bring value to people's lives.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Simbi.io - Intermediate Full Stack Software Engineer

Vancouver, BC

Apr 2022 - Dec 2022

- Rebuilt core app functionalities to cater to rapid user growth in Next.js with the help of Redux, GraphQL, and MaterialUI yielding better scalability and higher user retention.
- Designed PostgreSQL database by refactoring current schema with new tables and relationships to satisfy product requirements without causing data corruption, improved the speed of data queries and the integrity of stored information.
- Developed RESTful APIs and handled event-driven hooks for new features with complex database updates.
- Troubleshooted and debugged codes with CI/CD pipelines before delivering new features.
- Collaborated with other engineers as well as reviewed, and audited their code on Gitlab.
- Wrote technical documentation with Docusaurus on new features and upgrades.

PledgX Inc. - Full Stack Software Developer

Toronto, ON

May 2021 - Mar 2022

- Architected the company's core application for general contractors using ReactJS and Python Flask from scratch to production. This app attracted public/private sectors and helped the company to receive its first investment.
- Revamped MySQL database schema, implemented the new structure into server-side code for better logic and less redundancy.
- Built, deployed, and maintained application running on GCP infrastructure, configured NGINX as a web server. to improve the software delivery process.
- Developed Python and C++ scripts for multiple internal services to automatically scrape more than 180,000 records of construction bidding data; read and extract data from PDF files and update to the database.

International Financial Data Services (IFDS) - Software developer

Toronto. ON

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

• Worked with Java, Maven configuration, Mockito JUnit tests, Spring framework, Agile methodology.

NAPA Global - Full Stack Software Developer

Danang, Vietnam

May 2019 - Aug 2019

• Worked with Angular 8, Node.js, MongoDB, Bootstrap to build a reactive web application with RESTful API

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: TypeScript/Javascript, Python, HTML/CSS, Java, C++, UNIX/Shell
- Front-end: ReactJS, Next.js, Redux, GraphQL, Angular 8+, Material UI, TSS/Emotion, Bootstrap
- Back-end: NodeJS, Flask, ParsePlatform, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- DevOps & other tools: AWS, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Git, Linux/Ubuntu, Jira, Confluence

EDUCATION

Ryerson University - B.Sc., Computer Science

Sep 2017 - May 2021

Honored degree majored in Computer Science, minored in Finance

OTHERS

• **First prize** - Best Overall Solution in WTIM Ryerson - WeDesignTech Hackathon 2021 for a mobile app **GREENBIE** to promote eco-friendly practice with a rewarding system